Guide to the Barry Whitehead collection of horse prints: Breeder and Sportsman Horseman Magazine, 1755-1934
Department of Special Collections
Barry Whitehead collection of horse prints: Breeder and Sportsman Horseman Magazine,
1755-1934
Special Collections M0783
Whitehead, Barry
2.5 linear ft. (23 prints; 67 magazine covers or parts)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Barry Whitehead, 1996
Access terms
Whitehead, Barry, collector.; Alken, William, engraver.; Bentley, C., engraver.; Bird, Harington, painter.; Cameron, J., artist.; Cross, H.H., artist.; Hall, Harry, artist.; Harrup, John, publisher.; Herring, J.F., artist.; Hester, E.G., engraver.; Pollard, James, engraver.; Scanlon, Maurice S., artist.; Stock, C.R., engraver.; Stubbs, George Townly, engraver.; Stull, Henry, artist.; Voss, F.B., engraver.; Whitney, Frank, artist.; Wyttenbach, E., artist.; Britton & Rey.; Capewell Horse Nail Co.; Currier & Ives.; Horses.; Calendars.; Prints.
Container List
- "Harold," by Henry Stull. 27 x 37 cm. PlateVI, with full page genealogy and description. 1880 (Box 1)
- "Sainfoin," engraving by C.R. Stock, painting by Harington Bird, A.R.C.A. 41 x 51 cm. 1890 (Box 1)
- "Ayesbury Grand Steeple Chase; the Start, February 9, 1866," C. Bentley, Sculp; Wm Alken, Del 34 x 49 cm. (Box 1)
- "Breeder and Sportsman," San Francisco. Includes Britton & Rey lithograph and drawings by E. Wyttenbach. 1889, Sept 14 (Box 1)
- "Hindoo," by Henry Stull, 27 x 38 cm. Short text on mat. 1881 (Box 2)
- "Luke Blackburn," by Henry Stull. 27 x 38 cm. Plate VII, with full page genealogy and description. Also, full page genealogy and description for "Iroquois," but no picture. 1881 (Box 2)
- "Maud S.," by Maurice S. Scanlon. 28 x 37 cm. With caption. 1880 (Box 2)
- "Parole," by Harry Hall, Newmarket. 28 x 38 cm. Plate III, with full page genealogy and description. 1879 (Box 2)
- "Hindoo," same plate and description as #1. Better condition. (Box 2)
- "Anvil," drawn and engraved by George Townly Stubbs, London. 21 x 26 cm. 1794 (Box 3)
- "Dexter." drawn by J. Cameron; lithograph by Currier & Ives, New York. 27 x 38 cm. 1871 (Box 3)
- "Iroquois," by Henry Stull. 27 x 38 cm. (description in box 2, folder 2, for conservation work) 1881 (Box 3)
- "Moses," drawn and engraved by James Pollard, London. 38 x 48 cm. 1822 (Box 3)
- "Leamington," Armstrong & Co., Boston, copyright S.F. Cassino. 28 x 38 cm. 1881 (Box 3)
- "Bonnie Scotland," Armstrong & Co., Boston, copyright S.F. Cassino. 28 x 38 cm. 1881 (Box 3)
- "Aylesbury Grand Steeple Chase; Coming In, February 9, 1866," C. Bentley, Sculp.; W. Alken, Del., London. 33 x 48 cm. (Box 3)
- "Favonius," engraved by E.G. Hester; painted by Harry Hall. 45 x 50 cm. (Box 3)
- "Billy Barton," painted and engraved by F.B. Voss, copyright at the Sign of the Gosden Head, New York. Plate 3. 34 x 37 cm. 1834 (Box 3)
- "Industry," engraved by C. and G. Hunt, painted by J.F. Herring, and published by John Moore, London. 40 x 48 cm. (Box 3)
- "Childers; the fleetest horse that ever run at Newmarket," Houston fecit; Seymour delint; published March. Hand colored. 30 x 35 cm. 1755 (Box 3)
- "The Portraiture of Lamprey," Houston fecit, Seymour delint. Hand colored. 30 x 35 cm. 1755, Mar (Box 3)
- "Ormonde," Manchester, John Harrup. 59 x 75 cm. [c.1886] (Map-case Map Case)
- "Galopin," [Manchester, John Harrup.] 59 x 75 cm. [c.1875] (Map-case Map Case)
- "The Celebrated Trotting Mare Lucy, Passing the Judges Stand," New York, Currier & Ives. 49 x 69 cm. [c.1872] (Map-case Map Case)